ANTONIA VILLA

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

I'm a full stack developer who refuses to believe data visualization's only role is as a scientific tool for data analytics. Before I took the dive into the engineering world, I worked as an analyst by day and an artist by night. I quickly discovered data representation needed a makeover. Visualization can break down numbers into patterns, trends, and make information interesting and even beautiful. My goal is to make data more accessible to the people and empower them to learn from it rather than shy away from its complexities. A piece of art can inspire, impress, and make you think, and so should a good data visualization.

SKILLS

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React BACK END: Node JS, Python, Django, MongoDB

ANALYTICAL: PostgreSQL, mySQL, Tableau, VBA, Google Analytics

DESIGN: Photoshop CS6, Adobe Creative Suite

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY: Seattle, WA

Student Nov 2017 - Mar 2018

- Develop back-end web applications using MVC frameworks; implement a dynamic front-end
- Implement web APIs from third-party sites
- Deploy secure applications to cloud services (Heroku)
- Collaborate on teams using an agile development workflow and collaboration practices in Git

CUSTOMER PORTFOLIOS: Boston, MA

Marketing Analyst

Jul 2015 - Oct 2017

- Interfaced with account teams, data scientists, and marketing specialists to provide best-in-class, analytics-based marketing solutions for established E-commerce and Retail clients
- Define research questions and analytical topics, including: campaign assessment, customer segmentation, marketing opportunities and customer engagement
- Developed, executed, and reported on multi-touch Customer Lifecycle Marketing
- Designed and maintained online dashboards to present KPIs to internal and external stake holders; included developing data structures, parameters, and dynamic content through SQL and Tableau

PATIENTS LIKE ME, INC.: Cambridge, MA

Acquisition Analyst

Apr 2014 – Jul 2015

- Develop multivariate ad testing and monitor daily results to optimize cost per acquisition
- Design and implement recruitment project plans including budget structuring, KPI, and ad strategy
- Manage simultaneously projects ranging in scope from 100 acquisitions in one month to 100,000 acquisitions over two years

MIT ANNUAL FUND: Cambridge, MA

Data Analyst, Class and Affinity Giving

Aug 2012 - Apr 2015

- Influence strategic decisions by creating interactive tools to display data, including writing macros, creating data models, and data visualizations
- Design user-friendly reports to facilitate new and improved functionality for departmental data
- Initiated analysis of 750 alumni survey responses by constructing a template for data entry, regularly reviewing its efficiency to ensure optimal workflow

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY: Web Development Immersion Certificate HARVARD EXTENSION SCHOOL: Programming Certificate

Nov 2017 - Feb 2018 Jan 2016 - May 2017

HAMILTON COLLEGE: Bachelor of Arts, Mathematics and Fine Arts

May 2012

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

BRA Certified Artist – works currently showing in Metro Boston Area Recipient of Artist Fellowship Grant, Somerville Arts Council